

Gevorg Yeghikyan

Urban Data Scientist

Phone: +393248767384

Google Scholar: https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=QCpK8mYAAAAJ&hl=en

Website: https://lexparsimon.github.io/
Email: gevorgyeghikyan@gmail.com

Holding a PhD in spatial data science, I study cities with the mathematical apparatus of data science, machine learning, and complex systems. I'm currently a postdoctoral researcher at the Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining Lab (KDD Lab), a research group focusing on modeling urban mobility and socio-economic dynamics at the Italian National Research Council. Working with urban planning firms, municipalities, UNDP, GIZ, and the World Bank, I also consult urban development, master planning, (E-) mobility, and transportation projects worldwide.

EXPERIENCE

ISTI-CNR, Pisa, Italy

Dec 2020 - present

PostDoctoral researcher

I conduct research on **data science** methods for **urban planning and mobility**. My main focus are spatio-temporal statistical modelling of urban phenomena, operations research for optimal urban planning, and deep learning, particularly graph neural networks for urban mobility prediction.

KDD Lab, Pisa, Italy

Mar 2018 - Nov 2020

Research assistant

Within the context of my PhD research, I have been involved in developing **spatial data analysis** methods and algorithms for modelling the connection between urban mobility and urban socio-economic characteristics.

Bruno Kessler Foundation, Trento, Italy

May - Aug 2019

Visiting scholar

As part of my PhD research, I spent a three-month research period at FBK Trento, developing a **neural network** algorithm for predicting urban mobility flows.

GIZ, Germany Jan - May 2019

Big Data for urban planning consultant

I have been involved as an external consultant in the development of a concept paper and Terms of Reference for the "Big Data for urban planning" project commissioned by GIZ Armenia for the cities of Yerevan, Minsk and Tbilisi.

Format Elf Architekten, Töging am Inn, Germany

Feb - Aug 2015

Urban and architectural planner

I worked on urban and architectural masterplans, GIS analyses, and feasibility studies.

Ingenhoven Architects, Düsseldorf, Germany

June 2014 - Feb 2015

Urban planner

I worked on large scale urban planning and design projects in Germany and abroad.

EDUCATION

Scuola Normale Superiore, Pisa, Italy

Nov 2017 - Nov 2020

PhD in spatial data science

My PhD research focused on developing data science methods and algorithms for understanding how socio-economic

characteristics of urban locations are related to the mobility flows between them. The research concluded in a doctoral thesis (cum laude) and 6 publications in top journals and conferences in computer and data science.

Städelschule Architecture Class, Frankfurt am Main, Germany

Oct 2015 - Oct 2017

Msc. in urban planning

National University of Architecture and Construction, Yerevan, Armenia

Sep 2010 - May 2014

Bsc. in architecture and urban planning

SKILLS

- R, Python data science kit (geopandas, numpy, scikit-learn, pytorch, scipy)
- SQL, PostgreSQL + PostGIS
- QGIS + Python, ArcGIS
- Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator
- PTV Vissim, AutoCAD, Rhino

LANGUAGES

English, Russian, Armenian (Full professional proficiency), **German, Italian** (Professional working proficiency), **French** (Limited working proficiency)